Contact

Genfeng.liu@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/geraldlgf (LinkedIn) Github.com/genfengl (GitHub Repository) Geraldliu-dev.netlify.app (Porfolio)

Core Technologies

Programming languages

- Javascript
- Python
- Typescript

Frontend

- React.is
- Tailwind CSS
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Material UI

Backend

- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Firebase
- PostgreSQL
- Flask

Currently learning

- Kotlin
- Jest
- Next.js
- C#

Languages

- English (Native or Bilingual)
- Mandarin (Native or Bilingual)
- Cantonese (Native or Bilingual)

Gerald Liu

Software Engineer | Javascript | React | Node.js | Tailwind CSS | Python Melbourne, Australia

Summary

I'm passionate about generating sustainable, efficient and agile solutions to problems.

I developed strong research and analytical skills that enabled me to learn fast, be critical and develop deeper understandings of sustainability-related concepts.

Huge fan of creating and building things or simply solving any kinds of problems. I believe by creating performant and sustainable solutions to business problems, I can contribute towards resolving numerous environmental issues and make the community around me a little better.

Experience

General Assembly 4 months

Software Engineering Immersive Student September 2022 – November 2022 (3 months)

Project 3: ChatUp - Instant Messenger App November 2022 (1 week)

Going beyond course material, I studied the docs for Firebase and Tailwind with two other teammates to create an instant messenger application with a Discord theme UI.

Full CRUD database manipulation implemented through Firestore provided in Firebase.

Used a variety of react hooks, such as useState, useRef, useContext, useReducer, and useEffect to implement frontend interactions. Implemented a dark-mode switch and hover effects for certain elements using tailwind to improve user experience.

Project 2: NTMY - E-commerce Store October 2022 - November 2022 (1 week) A full MERN stack e-commerce store app developed with two teammates. Implemented a search function using the MongoDB Atlas Search, and a model payment process using Stripe API.

Implemented a variety of responsive react-bootstrap components, such as a carousel, an offcanvas, cards, and a navbar.

User authentication was implemented using the Passport middleware.

Gained experience in working collaboratively on Github.

Project 1: Tangerine's Cat Food Catalogue – CRUD App September 2022 – October 2022 (1 week)

A full stack web app for indexing a large quantity of cat food products with a complete RESTful API.

Used the Passport middleware to implement the user authentication. Used bootstrap components for styling.

Project 0: Tic-Tac-Toe – Web Page Game September 2022 - September 2022 (1 week)

My first ever javascript/HTML/CSS project.

I gained a lot of hands-on experience in Document Object Model (DOM) manipulation, conditional statements, loops and eventListeners.

Created a theme switcher with four theme choices and some basic blinking animations and hover effects using vanilla CSS.

Familiarised myself with both flexbox and grid layouts.

EY

1 month

Summer Intern
August 2016 – August 2016 (1 month)
Hong Kong

Education

University of Melbourne

Master of Science – MS, Agricultural Sciences (2021 – 2022) H1 – First Class Honours

University College London

Integrated Masters with Honours – Msci, Information Management for Business (2014 – 2018)

2.1 – Second Class Honours Upper Division

The ISF Academy

International Baccalaureate Diploma Programme (IBDP) (2012-2014) Score: 41